<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Networking | Jonathon Rossi]]></title>
  <link href="http://jonorossi.com/blog/categories/networking/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jonorossi.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-25T18:04:59+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://jonorossi.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jonathon Rossi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardware Network Firewall]]></title>
    <link href="http://jonorossi.com/blog/2008/04/26/hardware-network-firewall/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-26T06:32:22Z</updated>
    <id>http://jonorossi.com/blog/2008/04/26/hardware-network-firewall</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/files/2008/VIAITX.jpg"></p>

<p>I have been planning to build a standalone hardware firewall for my home network for quite a long time. I brought a 1Ghz VIA ITX
17cm x 17cm motherboard towards the end of last year for the firewall but couldn't find a decent case to mount the board in.</p>

<p>I have been looking on eBay for months for a cheap old rackmount network switch or router that I can gut and mount the board inside,
but nothing has come up cheap. Yesterday I won an eBay auction for a brand new 1U rackmount case, a little flashy for a firewall,
but I got the case cheap and it has plenty of space for all the components compared to an old network switch.</p>

<p>I was always planning to install <a href="http://www.ipcop.org/">IPCop</a>, but after some research I found both <a href="http://m0n0.ch/wall/">m0n0wall</a> and one of its children <a href="http://www.pfsense.org/">pfSense</a>
seem more polished. I know from playing around with IPCop that it wasn't the easiest firewall to configure and with m0n0wall/pfSense
having a single configuration XML file that I can commit into Subversion it is shaping up nicely. pfSense is a fork of m0n0wall and
has more features but requires a slightly more powerful chip and more RAM. pfSense has several features I am interested in that m0n0wall
doesn't, including a traffic shaper and installable packages, which includes both <a href="http://www.snort.org/">snort</a> and <a href="http://www.squid-cache.org/">squid</a>. I am now planning to install
pfSense because it seems a lot more polished than IPCop, but I haven't tried out pfSense myself.</p>

<p>Once I get all the hardware together I'll post further details of my experience. If you have done something similar yourself or just want
to voice your opinion then I am interested in hearing your comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HP ProCurve 1800-24G Gigabit Network Switch]]></title>
    <link href="http://jonorossi.com/blog/2008/02/17/hp-procurve-1800-24g-gigabit-network-switch/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-17T13:20:32Z</updated>
    <id>http://jonorossi.com/blog/2008/02/17/hp-procurve-1800-24g-gigabit-network-switch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a follow up to <a href="/blog/2008/01/08/network-switches-and-the-dell-experience/">my post about getting a 24 port gigabit network switch</a>, I have purchased one, but not the one I had planned to.</p>

<p>I did some more research recently before I ordered one and discovered the <a href="http://www.hp.com/rnd/products/switches/ProCurve_Switch_1800_Series/overview.htm">HP ProCurve 1800-24G</a>. I never considered HP in any
previous research because I expected them to be expensive, however this one turned out slightly cheaper than the Netgear GS724T that
I was planning to buy.</p>

<p><a href="/files/2008/HPProCurve180024G.jpg"><img src="/files/2008/HPProCurve180024G.jpg"></a></p>

<p>The 1800-24G has many of the same features as the GS724T, including lifetime warranty. However, one difference is that the 1800-24G has
a less than 4.7 microsecond 100Mbps latency compared to less than 20 microseconds with the GS724T. The 1800-24G then also has a less
than 3.0 microsecond 1000Mbps latency.</p>

<p>If you or your employer is looking for a gigabit network switch then you should seriously consider the HP ProCurve 1800-24G over cheaper
brands. I have been really happy with it since I got it nearly a week ago.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Domain names for every network device]]></title>
    <link href="http://jonorossi.com/blog/2008/01/15/domain-names-for-every-network-device/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-15T12:09:24Z</updated>
    <id>http://jonorossi.com/blog/2008/01/15/domain-names-for-every-network-device</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With IPv6 <a href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20080102-icann-to-add-ipv6-addresses-for-root-dns-servers.html">around the corner</a> it will become mainstream some time in the near future for all computers to be assigned a routable
IPv6 address. A trend that I'm pretty sure will start in the near future is for network devices in everyone's homes will have a
subdomain of a personal domain name. One pretty big reason is because it will be difficult to remember and type an address like
<code>2001:0db8:0000:0000:0000:0000:1428:57ab</code>, compared to something like "john.johnsmithhome.com". I see this getting popular because
more people are starting to remotely access their home network with things like Windows Home Server.</p>

<p>According to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv6">Wikipedia</a>, IPv6 provides us with "more than a trillion addresses per square centimeter of surface on the planet".
As mentioned on Wikipedia, not all this address space will be used for allocation to devices, however it is very unlikely we will
ever run out again. We could start leasing IPv6 addresses to another planet ;).</p>

<p>With all its advantages, IPv6 will cause some problems, it will make it harder for network administrators because IPv6 addresses
are so much longer to type and compare. But by far the biggest problem I foresee by assigning a routable IP address to every network
device is that a direct inbound connection can be made by anyone to any network device anywhere. Currently, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_address_translation">NAT</a> protects many
insecure computers in home networks because it does not allow direct connections to network devices unless explicitly set up.
Therefore, home routers will need to be shipped with a firewall that blocks all incoming traffic by default and allows for rules
to be created to open specific ports. End users are going to have to be made more aware that protecting individual machines is more
important than it has been.</p>

<p>A little off topic, but I have asked myself the question before but could never work it out. Why are domain names right to left?
Does anyone know?</p>

<p>Wouldn't "http://com.example.mypc:8080/something/" make more sense compared to "http://mypc.example.com:8080/something/".</p>

<p>I can just imagine IntelliSense for domain names, it would be so sweet. Typing "com.google." would display a list with "www", "mail",
"maps", etc. It would also be useful for the "com.example." example above where you might not remember the full hostname and your
browser could help you out by asking the Domain Name System.</p>

<p>Since the domain name system is a tree of domain names where the subdomains are resolved from the top level domain name (TLD),
resolving left to right makes more sense.</p>

<p>The "com.example.mypc" example above reads like, use the HTTP protocol to connect to the host under the "com" TLD, the "example"
domain name and the "mypc" subdomain" on the application port "8080", then request the resource "/something/".</p>

<p>Most hierarchical representations like code namespaces, web site breadcrumbs and file systems work display left to right. I am
fully aware that this is not going to change, I just wondered why domain names were put in this format to start with.</p>

<p>So are you looking forward to the worldwide deployment of IPv6, or are you happy with IPv4? I know I am looking forward to IPv6,
being a computer geek that loves to play with networks. I can't wait until I will be able to set up a 'real' DNS server at home
and host things wherever I like without worrying about port forwarding and conflicting ports being used by other computers via UPnP.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Network Switches and 'The Dell Experience']]></title>
    <link href="http://jonorossi.com/blog/2008/01/08/network-switches-and-the-dell-experience/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-08T13:26:46Z</updated>
    <id>http://jonorossi.com/blog/2008/01/08/network-switches-and-the-dell-experience</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first real blog post about something other than releases of Castle Visual Studio Integration. I appreciate any
feedback on my content, writing style, or my choice of topic.</p>

<p>Last year I attempted to contact Dell Australia to get prices for their PowerConnect network switch range. I was and still
am in the market for a 24 port gigabit network switch.</p>

<p>The Dell customer service was terrible. I rang up multiple times a day for over a week. After waiting on hold for a long
time I got to speak to operators from a call centre in India. I thought Michael Dell came back to improve the company, he must
have missed the customer service or maybe just Australia. He did very well with the rest of the company, I own a Dell laptop
and am very happy with it.</p>

<p>From ringing up so many times I was not only frustrated because they couldn't understand me, but I couldn't understand them either.
The line quality was pretty bad, as well as there being an echo and a delay in the line. They also would always ask you for your
phone number to ring you back because the line would drop out pretty often, however they would never ring you back if the line did
drop out. I was also disappointed that very few of the operators I attempted talking to even knew what a Dell PowerConnect was.
Come on, these guys are meant to be selling expensive gear here and I know more about what they sell than they do. I even rang up
the number for the 5000+ employee companies (or something like that) and was greeted by a friendly Australian girl, however that is
as far as my luck went, I was back into the call centre after she forwarded me.</p>

<p>One call I made actually got me to a consultant, however he could only give me "estimates" of prices, what good are estimates, I was
asking for a quote. I got half way through asking for prices for several models and the line dropped out. A lot of what this consultant
said didn't make sense. The prices he provided are actually more expensive than the prices I obtained from Dell over a year ago.</p>

<p>I finally gave up trying to get prices from them; something must have been telling me that Dell network switches are not worth looking at.</p>

<p>I am currently considering purchasing a <a href="http://www.netgear.com/Products/Switches/SmartSwitches/GS724T.aspx">Netgear GS724T</a> 24-port gigabit switch. Both the Netgear switch and an equivalent Dell have
the same switching capacity of 48Gbps, so they are pretty comparable.</p>

<p>I don't need (and can't afford) a Cisco, so I am looking at Netgear, Linksys and D-Link. The switch will be used at home so it isn't going
to be flogged all day long and doesn't need to have all the fancy VLAN and VPN support that Cisco switches have. Have you got one of these
type switches or used them before? Do you prefer one brand over another? Do you have any recommendations for me?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
